(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Lapis Lazuli
TAKANE LUI
ホロライブ秘密結社holoX
鷹嶺ルイ
幹部
Hololive Secret Society holoX
Takane Lui
Executive
NEXT CHAPTER
Lapis Lazuli
鷹嶺ルイ 重大告知 LIVE
Takane Lui Major Announcement LIVE
死の国中　愉快に乗っかって
Riding happily through the land of death
目ん玉草さを　押し付けられてる
Being forced to accept the eyeball grass
何から何まで
From everything to everything
仕草を辞めて　また耳鳴りなら
Stop your deeds, and if it's ringing in the ears again
聞きお上手に　頷き合わせてる
Cleverly listening and nodding along
なぎ倒し　こしらえ
Mowing down and preparing
さあ　駄々々々　黙れ　黙りたまえよ
Now, stop being selfish, shut up, please be quiet
癒えない内　そんな強い言葉は
While it's still not healed, such strong words
少しだけ　静かにしてほしいね
I want you to be a little quiet
あぁ　私達　大亡命
Ah, we are on a great exile
世界　デデデデ　僕やややや
World (De-de-de-de), me (ya-ya-ya-ya)
果たせ　その日まで
Until the day we fulfill it
レレレレ　業やややや
(Re-re-re-re), karma (ya-ya-ya-ya)
雨降る夜にも　やややや
Even on rainy nights (ya-ya-ya-ya)
今日も起きない　そっちのけだね
Not waking up today either, ignoring it all
家になるから　私一人でも　やっておきますね
Because I'll become a house, I'll do it by myself
全て　全て　全て任せて
Everything, everything, leave it all to me
それをささせてよ　私のことなの　わかっているでしょう
Let me do that, it's about me, you understand right?
死の国中　愉快に乗っかって
Riding happily through the land of death
目ん玉草いま　今日も明日も　過ぎていくのでしょう
Eyeball grass now, today and tomorrow will surely pass by
みんな来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for coming!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
一緒に歌ってくれたのは、ハコス・ベールズちゃんでーす！
The one who sang with me is Hakos Baelz-chan!
ルイ姉ー！
Lui-nee!
嬉しいー！
I'm so happy!
I'm happy too!
花瓶に　水を　あげましょう
Let's water the vase
時の中　しおれたこと　忘れてた
I'd forgotten it had withered within time
さあ　駄々々々　黙れ　黙りたまえよ
Now, stop being selfish, shut up, please be quiet
癒えない内　そんな強い言葉は
While it's still not healed, such strong words
少しだけ　静かにしてほしいね
I want you to be a little quiet
あぁ　私達　大亡命
Ah, we are on a great exile
今と未来　見たかったはずなのに
Even though we should have wanted to see the present and future
世界　デデデデ　僕やややや
World (De-de-de-de), me (ya-ya-ya-ya)
見えぬその日まで　ドトトト　業やややや
Until the day we can't see (do-to-to-to), karma (ya-ya-ya-ya)
この世のことわり　やややや　今は　ゼゼゼゼ
The truth of this world (ya-ya-ya-ya), now (ze-ze-ze-ze)
僕ササササ　あなたの街まで　形作るは　バッテン
Me (sa-sa-sa-sa), all the way to your town, forming an 'X'
さあ　世界　デデデデ　僕やややや
Now, world (De-de-de-de), me (ya-ya-ya-ya)
果たせ　その日まで
Until the day we fulfill it
レレレレ　業やややや　雨降る夜にも　やややや
(Re-re-re-re), karma (ya-ya-ya-ya), even on rainy nights
世界　デデデデ　僕らやややや　約束の地まで
World (De-de-de-de), us (ya-ya-ya-ya), to the promised land
さあ　駆け抜け　待って　待ってて　僕
Now, run through, wait, wait for me
オーバーロード
Overdo
ばかばっか
Baka Bakka
もういいじゃん　ムキになっちゃって　カッコつけて
It's fine already, getting all serious, trying to look cool
カッコよくない　そういうの　嫌になってんだ
It's not cool, I'm getting sick of that kind of thing
放っといてよ　死にたくない
Leave me alone, I don't want to die
もういいじゃん　ヤケになってんの　嫉妬したり
It's fine already, are you being desperate? Being jealous...
じっとできない　聞こえないよ　耳塞いだって
Can't stay still, I can't hear you, even if I plug my ears
言ってってくるじゃん　しんどいな
You keep telling me, it's exhausting
僕は誰も　覗かないよ
I won't peek at anyone
だから僕のこと　そっとしておいて
So just leave me be
ウザいだけのバカに　ハイハイハイ　ウケる　またの越し待ってるねだとか
To the annoying fools, "Yeah yeah yeah, funny. I'll be waiting for your next visit."
本当は怯えてる　吠えるだけの弱虫だったんだ
In reality, you're scared, just a weakling who only knows how to bark
痛いくせに耐えて　ハイハイハイ　いつも平気なフリばっかりなの
Even though it hurts, you endure it, "Yeah yeah yeah," always just pretending to be fine
僕は壁を貼ったまま笑う
I laugh while keeping my walls up
それ以上　近づかないで　怖いじゃん
Don't come any closer than that, it's scary
ばかばっか
Baka Bakka
やだ　ばかばっか
No, Baka Bakka
もういいじゃん　まだ怒ってんの　放っといてよ
It's fine already, are you still angry? Leave me alone
ホッとできない　見ないように　目を逸らしたって
I can't feel at ease, even if I look away to avoid seeing you
付いてくるじゃん　やっぱり
You keep following me, of course
転がったら起きればいいじゃん　失ったら探せばいいじゃん
If you fall over, just get back up; if you lose something, just look for it
それでよくない？
Isn't that fine?
間違ったら直せばいいじゃん　嫌だったら辞めればいいじゃん
If you make a mistake, just fix it; if you don't like it, just quit
…じゃない、よくない
...not, it's not good
僕なんて誰も望まないよ
No one wants someone like me
だから僕のことそっとして嫌なこと全部大丈夫だと
So just leave me alone, and if you could say everything bad is okay
言えたらいいのにな
I wish I could say that
思えたらいいのにな
I wish I could feel that way
違うよって出鱈目な大正解　いつも僕はそんなロールなど
'That's wrong,' a nonsensical correct answer. I'm always playing that kind of role
また言いたいこと殺すからもう忘れてくれ
I'll kill what I want to say again, so just forget about it
うわははは　歌いたげのバカにハイハイハイ
Uwahahaha! Yes, yes, yes, to the fool who wants to sing
ウケるまた残しまってるねだとか
That's funny, 'You're leaving things behind again,' they say
本当は怯えてる吠えるだけの弱虫だったった
Actually, I was just a coward who barks because I'm scared
痛い口に耐えてハイハイハイ　いつも平気なふりばっかなの僕は
Enduring my painful words, yes, yes, yes. I'm always just pretending to be fine
壁を張ったまま笑う
Laughing while keeping my walls up
それ以上近づかないで　降下
Don't come any closer than that. Descent.
ほんとバカばっか　いい加減ばっか
Truly just full of fools, full of irresponsibility
飛んだバズばっか　だせえ待って
Full of crazy buzz... it's lame, wait
そんな言葉吐く僕もやっぱどうしようもないんだ　罰点境界
I, who spit out such words, am also hopeless after all. Penalty boundary
痛いことか吐いてらんないな
I can't even spit out painful things
死ねるって僕も口ばっかだね
Saying 'I could die,' I'm just all talk too
今日も壁を張ったまま笑う
Today again, laughing while keeping my walls up
それ以上近づかないで
Don't come any closer than that
怖いじゃん　バカバカ
It's scary, isn't it? Fool, fool
ほらバカバカ
See, fool, fool
はい、ということで！重大告知ライブ、始まりましたー！
Yes, and with that! The Major Announcement Live has begun!
皆様待たかねー！HoloXの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します！
Wait is over, everyone! I'm Takane Lui, the female executive of HoloX!
ということでみんな見えとるぞ、コメント。
So, I can see everyone's comments.
あ、拍手いっぱいありがとうな。拍手いっぱいありがとう。
Oh, thank you for all the applause. Thank you for all the applause.
ということで本日のハッシュタグはですね、こちら。
So, today's hashtag is this one.
あ、こちらにありますね。
Oh, it's over here.
えー、ハッシュタグ鷹嶺ルイ重大告知ライブでたくさん、つぶやい... つぶやきじゃないわｗ
Um, please use the hashtag #TakaneLuiMajorAnnouncementLive to tweet... not tweet, I mean...
ポストしてくれると嬉しいです。みんな今すぐポストしてください！
I'd be happy if you could post. Everyone, please post right now!
ということで、もう1曲目、2曲目と『Overdose』『ばかばっか』と熱い曲が続いたんですけど
So, the first and second songs, 'Overdose' and 'Baka Baka', were both very intense.
1曲目からなんと特別ゲストが登場してくださいました！
And to my surprise, a special guest joined me from the very first song!
ちょっとお喋りしたいと思いますので呼びたいと思います。べーちゃん！
I'd like to chat for a bit, so I'll call her out. Bae-chan!
おれ、おれ、おれ、あれ？
Wait, wait, wait, huh?
きたー！
I'm here!
Whats up! 我はカオス、終わりの果て、大公。混沌の化身、死に狂いのバラ、汝の友、ホロENのハコス・ベールズです！フー！
What's up! I am Chaos, the Archduke of the end. The incarnation of chaos, the death-crazed rose, your friend, HoloEN's Hakos Baelz! Hoo!
ということでべーちゃんとはね、『Overdose』を一緒に歌わせて頂いたんですけど
So, I sang 'Overdose' together with Bae-chan.
めっちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
嬉しい！私も嬉しい。べーちゃんとは本当に一緒に歌いたくて。
I'm happy! I'm happy too. I really wanted to sing with Bae-chan.
同じです！
Same here!
めっちゃ... いや、ルイ姉の曲めっちゃ好きなんで、僕。ね、めっちゃかっこよくて。
I really... I mean, I love Lui-nee's songs. They're so cool.
いやーようやく歌いましたね！
We finally got to sing together!
歌いましたね！ね、『ばかばっか』ね、絶対べーちゃんに合うと思って。やっぱカオスなんでねｗ
We did! I thought 'Baka Baka' would definitely suit Bae-chan. Since she's Chaos after all.
ははは、いやめっちゃかっこいい！
Hahaha, no, it's really cool!
いや嬉しい、一緒に歌えて。ちょっとね、最後のほうちょっとやらかした。
I'm so glad we could sing together. But, I kind of messed up at the end.
え、嘘！？全然わかんなかったよ多分。
Wait, really? I don't think anyone noticed.
いや、多分ね、振りはね、言っていいこれ？
Well, maybe the choreography... can I say this?
いいよ。
Sure.
振りは元々なかったんだよ。んでなんかリハ中に「あ、ちょっと振り付けようか」みたいな話になってて
There wasn't any choreography originally. Then during rehearsal, we were like, "Should we add some movement?"
「え、やばい」って。ちょっと最後のとこ忘れちゃって、すみません、すみませんでした。
And I was like "Oh no". I forgot the last part, I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
いいよいいよ全然分からなかった。でもやっぱりさ、テンション上がっちゃうとね。
It's fine, I didn't notice at all. But you know, when the tension gets high...
わかる！
I know!
いや、でも楽しんでくれたんだよね、きっとね。
But I'm sure you enjoyed it, right?
めっちゃ楽しい！めちゃくちゃ楽しい！
It's so much fun! It's super fun!
嬉しい！私もべーちゃんの曲本当に大好きで。いつかべーちゃんの曲も挑戦したいな、なんて。
I'm glad! I really love your songs too, Bae-chan. I hope to try singing one of yours someday.
ぜひぜひ！聞きたい！聞きたい！
Please do! I want to hear it! I want to hear it!
一緒に歌ってくれますか？
Will you sing it with me?
いやもうぜひです！いや、ルイ姉の『サイコ』聞きたいかも。サイコ聞きたいかも。
Oh, definitely! I'd love to hear Lui-nee sing 'PSYCHO'. I'd love to hear 'PSYCHO'.
『サイコ』ね！『サイコ』難しいけど、え、ぜひ一緒に歌いましょう！
'PSYCHO'! It's a difficult one, but let's definitely sing it together!
歌いましょう！お願いします！
Let's do it! Please!
お願いします。なんだこれｗ
Please. What is this? lol
ということで、21時半からですね、ごろ... あ、21時半ごろにですね、重大告知を
So, at 9:30... around 9:30 PM, I have a major announcement...
重大告知ー！
Major announcement!
させていただきますので、もう少しお待ちいただけますと幸いです。
...to make, so please wait a little longer.
Big announcement at 9:30 PM JST! Thank you! Thank you a lot!
海外ニキも返信してくれるんじゃないかな。大丈夫かな。
I'm sure the overseas guys will respond. I hope so.
ということで、この後はですね、事前収録で来ていただいたゲストさんのパートになりますので
So, next up is the pre-recorded segment with our guests.
一緒に、じゃあVTRのキュー振りしてもらってもいいですか、べーちゃん？
Bae-chan, could you do the VTR intro with me?
イェーイ！
Yeah!
それでは皆さん、この後も楽しんでいってください！せーの！
Alright everyone, please continue to enjoy the show! One, two...
VTR、どうぞー！
VTR, here we go!
ホロホーク
作詞・作曲・編曲：すりぃ
Holo Hawk
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Three
単純で明快で簡単じゃない
Not simple, clear, or easy
まだ想像と妄想と偏見で Why
Still with imagination, delusions, and prejudice, why?
そりゃ完全な万全な設定じゃない
Well, that's not a perfect, complete setup
からかってくれないか
Won't you tease me?
外見と内面と偶像の不一致
Mismatch between appearance, inner self, and idol
この繊細さ敏感さを共有しよ
Let's share this delicacy and sensitivity
ほら冷静な表情は実際ちょーハイ
Look, my calm expression is actually super high
見つけてくれないか
Won't you find me?
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, pack it up and let's go
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectations, shoulder them and let's go
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, pack it up and let's go
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectations, shoulder them and let's go
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
Holo Hawk, Holo Hawk, but
高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃいや
Don't treat me like a flower on a high peak
あのね 誰も彼もわしと勘違い
You see, everyone's got the wrong idea about me
驚きのアイ
An eye-opening "I"
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
Holo Hawk, Holo Hawk, but
PONコツみがちょいあるだけで親近感
Just a bit of "PON" clumsiness makes me feel familiar
その際 その差異 その才 受け止めてよね
That occasion, that difference, that talent, please accept them
鷹嶺の未来 乾杯
A toast to the future of Takane
ノーイーグル
No Eagle
しっかりウォッチ
Watch closely
曖昧 You know
Vague, you know
ノーイーグル
No Eagle
狩りとか苦手
Not good at hunting
揺れるルイ姉
Swaying Lui-nee
一見クールね
Looks cool at first
意外とギャップ系
Surprisingly a "gap" type
イメージ大変身
Image transformation
OK?
大衆の歓声って内臓じゃない？
Aren't the crowd's cheers like internal organs?
ありゃ心配お悩み相談 三三九度も
Well, worry and trouble consultation, even the San-san-kudo ceremony
ただ正論や暴論の配信じゃない！
It's not just a stream of sound arguments or reckless opinions!
個人的見解 対 正解
Personal views vs. the correct answer
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
Holo Hawk, Holo Hawk, but
捕食しないさ だから怖がっちゃ嫌
I won't prey on you, so don't be afraid
ほらね 爪も羽もお洒落に研いで
Look, I've sharpened my claws and feathers stylishly
隠しちゃいない
I'm not hiding them
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
Holo Hawk, Holo Hawk, but
観察眼がちょいあるだけで緊張感
Just having a bit of observation skills brings tension
その際 その差異 その才 受け止めてよね
That occasion, that difference, that talent, please accept them
鷹まる時代 乾杯
A toast to the rising era
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, pack it up and let's go
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectations, shoulder them and let's go
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, pack it up and let's go
はいはい期待感 背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectations, shoulder them and let's go
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
Holo Hawk, Holo Hawk, but
高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃいや
Don't treat me like a flower on a high peak
あのね 誰も彼もわしと勘違い
You see, everyone's got the wrong idea about me
驚きのアイ
An eye-opening "I"
ホロホーク ホロホーク だけど
Holo Hawk, Holo Hawk, but
PONコツみがちょいあるだけで親近感
Just a bit of "PON" clumsiness makes me feel familiar
その際 その差異 その才 受け止めてよね
That occasion, that difference, that talent, please accept them
鷹嶺の未来 乾杯
A toast to the future of Takane
愛じゃん
It's love, isn't it
鷹まる時代 乾杯
A toast to the rising era
魔眼ウィンク
作詞・作曲・編曲：ななえら
Magan Wink
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Nanaera
Sorry
To be late
Do you remember me?
魅了る目と目が合ったら きっと落下
If our captivating eyes meet, you'll surely fall
足んない爪もう真っ赤っ赤だ
The missing claws are already bright red
それは Wink off Wink off 逃げてもずっと落下
That's Wink off Wink off, even if you run, you'll keep falling
I'm Crazy な台風の目
I'm the eye of a crazy typhoon
Showdown お目が高い 目に入れたって痛くないくらい
Showdown, you have a good eye, so much it wouldn't hurt to put you in my eye
ラララ クチバシに Sweet vengeance
La la la, sweet vengeance on the beak
憎しみならとっくに捨てた
If it's hatred, I threw it away long ago
怖がってんの？
Are you afraid?
あっそ
Oh, I see
Don't let me down
Eyes on me now
まだまだ
Not yet, not yet
Eyes on me now
安全じゃないから？
Because it's not safe?
健全じゃないから？
Because it's not sound?
それがなんだ Fantastic だね
So what, it's fantastic, isn't it
目には目を
An eye for an eye
Wink! La la la la la 魅せキララ Gimme
Wink! La la la la la, show me the sparkle, gimme
Wink! La la la la la 真っ赤っ赤だ
Wink! La la la la la, it's bright red
Oh EYE I I want you... バイバイ
Oh eye, I, I want you... bye bye
バイバイアンサー
Bye-bye answer
目に物見せる MY EYE EYE
I'll show you what's what, MY EYE EYE
Wink off
目を瞑るの半分ね
Closing my eyes halfway, right?
魔眼ウィンク
Magankou Wink
有能が絢爛降臨
A capable one descends in splendor
魔眼ウィンク
Magankou Wink
My god My god
ほらご覧 瞬く間に
Look, in the blink of an eye
EYE EYE
EYE'LL KILL YOU
Wink
後ろ指 指したいなら お好きにどうぞ
If you want to point fingers, feel free to do so
当方 当世 振り返らぬ 所詮の金輪際
I will never look back on this world, after all
お待たせ Suck out Suck out
Sorry to keep you waiting, suck out, suck out
おさらば 妬み Cut Cut
Goodbye to jealousy, cut cut
無礼な たたり目
Insolent evil eye
I'm coming back, coming back, coming back
目じゃない 夢中になれ Eyes on me now
Not a chance, lose yourself, eyes on me now
善良じゃないだろう 善良じゃないだろう
I'm probably not virtuous, right? I'm probably not virtuous, right?
それが どうしたんだ Franticだね
So what? It's frantic, isn't it?
目には目を
An eye for an eye
歯には羽を
A feather for a tooth
C'est la la vie
類は何を呼ぶ？
What does similarity attract?
C'est la vie 羽ばたきを知る
C'est la vie, knowing how to flap wings
Wink
目が離せない
Can't take my eyes off
完璧なウィンク
A perfect wink
C'est la la la lovin' 赤裸々 Gimme
C'est la la la lovin', nakedly gimme
A Wink C'est Lie-Lie-Liar 真っ赤っ赤だ
A Wink, C'est Lie-Lie-Liar, it's bright red
Oh eye eye eye want you で バイバイアンサー
Oh eye eye eye want you, so bye-bye answer
目に物見せる MY EYE EYE
I'll show you what's what, MY EYE EYE
もう目が離せない EYE
Can't take my eyes off anymore, eye
魔眼ウィンク
Magankou Wink
My god My god
ほらご覧 瞬く間に
Look, in the blink of an eye
EYE EYE EYE
EYE'LL KILL YOU
Wink
引けない
Can't pull back
なんてあり得ない
Is out of the question
後には引けない
No turning back now
無闇に披瀝さない
Don't reveal it recklessly
Fly...
いつだって突然のハラハラ 火花散らしで倍の力
Always a sudden thrill, sparks flying with double the power
待ったなし 媚びずダンシング
No waiting, dancing without flattery
しなやかなステップで交わしちゃおうぜ
Let's dodge with graceful steps
サラリーな社会が眠る頃に
When the salaryman society goes to sleep
パラリラ輩が跋扈するコロニー
In a colony where reckless groups roam
お決まりのラッシュ 表裏一体を
The usual rush, two sides of the same coin
潜り抜けて
Slipping through
平日は Shoo-be-doo-be-doo
Weekdays are Shoo-be-doo-be-doo
週末も Shoo-be-doo-be-doo
Weekends are Shoo-be-doo-be-doo
時にキツくハードに
Sometimes tough and hard
時に平和なバードに
Sometimes a peaceful bird
今宵 ひみつののしごと
Tonight, it's a secret job
綺羅煌々 狙って Bang bang bang
Shining brilliantly, aim and bang bang bang
外さない クリア
Won't miss, clear
威風堂々 目立って Run and gun
Majestic and striking, run and gun
未だに他に類を見ない
Still unparalleled elsewhere
意気揚々 迫って Bang bang bang
In high spirits, approaching, bang bang bang
悟られず カバー
Covering without being noticed
Here we go yo 気張ってさあ出番
Here we go yo, steel yourself, it's your turn
跡を濁さず
Leaving no trace
Take off
決して逃さない
Never letting go
燃えたぎる牙を剥くまで
Until baring burning fangs
決して汚さない
Never defiling
守る身の看板
The sign of protection
油断しきった 寝回し
Careless groundwork
お見舞いする 後の祭り
Delivering, but too late
響くヒールの音が お仕置きの合図
The sound of echoing heels is the signal for punishment
誰も彼も 特攻アイ
Everyone and anyone, suicide eye
年始から Shoo-be-doo-be-doo
From the start of the year, Shoo-be-doo-be-doo
年末も Shoo-be-doo-be-doo
Until the end of the year, Shoo-be-doo-be-doo
お任せあれ ハンドリング
Leave the handling to me
表に出せない 事後処理
Post-processing that can't be made public
もとい ひみつののしごと
Better yet, it's a secret job
綺羅煌々 狙って Bang bang bang
Shining brilliantly, aim and bang bang bang
外さない クリア
Won't miss, clear
威風堂々 目立って Run and gun
Majestic and striking, run and gun
しばしば 類は友を呼ぶ
Birds of a feather often flock together
意気揚々 迫って Bang bang bang
In high spirits, approaching, bang bang bang
悟られず カバー
Covering without being noticed
Here we go yo 気張ってさあ出番
Here we go yo, steel yourself, it's your turn
爪を剥き出し
Baring claws
Beat you
たかが虚業もどきと 侮るのなら
If you look down on it as a mere imitation...
多感に焦れてよしゃ できなくなってヤバさ呉れ！
Get impatiently frustrated and give me the danger of becoming unable to do it!
本音隠し 弱音なんてすぐやんね
Hiding true feelings, whining won't happen soon
混じり気ない ハートビート 揺らすこの世界
Pure heartbeats, shaking this world
最果てまで届くよう 鳴らした鐘
The bell rung to reach the furthest ends
裏の裏まで いたいけじゃう
Even the depths of the depths are naive
綺羅煌々 狙って Bang bang bang
Shining brilliantly, aim and bang bang bang
外さない クリア
Won't miss, clear
威風堂々 目立って Run and gun
Majestic and striking, run and gun
未だに他に類を見ない
Still unparalleled elsewhere
意気揚々 迫って Bang bang bang
In high spirits, approaching, bang bang bang
悟られず カバー
Covering without being noticed
Here we go yo 気張ってさあ出番
Here we go yo, steel yourself, it's your turn
跡を濁さず
Leaving no trace
Take off
今日もひみつの Take off
Today as well, a secret takeoff
媚びたこの鼻に
On this nose that flattered
泥を塗って放って描くわ
I'll smear mud, cast it away, and draw
情操 撫でた爪を立てて
Setting my claws on the stroked sentiments
信じられるものは
The only thing I can believe in
自分だけだと思い込んで
Is myself, so I'll keep convincing myself
進み続けて
and move forward
あの子みたいにすれば
If I act like that girl
君じゃそれは無理だ
That's impossible for you
言わせておけばいいさ
Let them say what they want
たった独り 逆境の先
All alone, beyond adversity
あいつらからフォーカス
Focus away from those people
私の邪魔 させやしない
I won't let anyone get in my way
分かってたがね 見据えた先
I knew it, looking at what's ahead
隘路抜けた空へと
Toward the sky through the narrow path
テイク 私を見なさいなんて
Take it, as if saying "look at me"
Bad Boy
失敗は止まった時
Failure is when you stop
今日も挑み果ての
Today as well, at the end of the challenge
君に無いものは無いと
There's nothing you don't have
信じられるものを
Until you find something
見つけ出すまで どんな日だって
To believe in, no matter the day
笑い飛ばすんだ
Just laugh it off
Na na na na...
あの子はもう終わりだ
That girl is already finished
これ以上は無いね
There's nothing more than this
言わせておけばいいさ
Let them say what they want
いつの日か寝ても覚めても
Someday, whether asleep or awake,
夢見てた大喝采
the cheers I dreamed of
私はここで死にたくない
I don't want to die here
一章の旅 逆境の先
A first chapter journey, beyond adversity
あいつらからフォーカス
Focus away from those people
私の邪魔 させやしない
I won't let anyone get in my way
分かってたがね 見据えた先
I knew it, looking at what's ahead
隘路抜けた空へと
Toward the sky through the narrow path
テイク 私を見なさいなんて
Take it, as if saying "look at me"
Bad Boy
Bad Boy...
誰かに言われなくたって
Even if nobody tells me
私の方が もっと嫌いだ
I hate myself even more
うるさいな 騒々しい視界を塞いで
Be quiet, blocking out the noisy view
惨めな理由を書き連ねる
Listing out miserable reasons
教室にずっと居残り
Staying behind in the classroom forever
窓の向こうに黒い影があって
There was a black shadow outside the window
何も言わずに こっちを見てた
Looking this way without saying anything
私はあなたに救われたくて泣くんじゃない
I'm not crying because I want you to save me
産声は 止められないもの
A first cry is something that can't be stopped
何千回と もう一度
Narrowly escaping death once again,
死に損なうのを
for the thousandth time
希望と絶望の夜中を纏って
Clad in a midnight of hope and despair
醜い光を許したのは
The one who allowed the ugly light
他ならない私だった
Was none other than myself
息をして
Take a breath
目を開けて
Open your eyes
これが最後かと記すのではないよ
I'm not writing it down as if it's the end
知りたくもないよ
I don't even want to know
優しいね
It's kind,
刻々と闇は寄り添って
the darkness draws closer moment by moment
解けない答えを塗りつぶした
Painting over the insoluble answers
冷たさを増した どしゃ降りの夜と
The night of downpouring rain grew colder
窓を挟んで 幽かに聞こえた
I heard it faintly through the window
それは祈るような すすり泣きだった
It was a sob that sounded like a prayer
私はあなたを 救える言葉を知らないけど
I don't know the words that can save you, but...
「寂しいね」って 声をかけた
I spoke to you, saying, "It's lonely, isn't it?"
何千回ともう一度 死に損なを
For the thousandth time, once more, a failure to die
希望と絶望のような 顔を纏って
Wearing a face like hope and despair
何千回ともう一度 息をあなたへ
For the thousandth time, once more,
a breath towards you
私も続くよ 窓の向こう側で
I will follow too, on the other side of the window
醜い光を 愛せたととき
When I could love the ugly light
終わらせなかった 産声を
The first cry that I didn't let end...
歌にしよう
I'll make it a song
特報
Special News
戦う理由は、一つじゃない
The reason for fighting is not just one.
Takane Lui 2nd Album LAPIS LAZULI
2025.12.03
全国CDショップにて予約開始！
Pre-orders start at CD shops nationwide!
GAMERSにてリリース記念ミニライブ開催決定！
Release commemorative mini-live to be held at GAMERS!
Stay Tuned.
はい！ということで、今特報を見ていただきましたが、
Yes! So, you've just seen the special news,
なんと、鷹嶺ルイ、12月3日に自身のセカンドアルバム『Lapis Lazuli』を発売することが決定しましたー！
and Takane Lui's second album "Lapis Lazuli" is set to be released on December 3rd!
ということで、なんとですね、今回は鷹嶺史上初の、全国、全国のショップで買える全国流通版ということで、
So, this time, it's the first ever nationwide release for Takane, available at shops all across the country.
また一つ夢が叶っちゃいました！みんなのおかげです、ありがとう！
Another dream has come true! It's all thanks to everyone, thank you!
えー、ファーストに続きまして、リバティに続きまして、セカンドなんですけども、
Following the first one, and Liberty, this is the second one,
今回は『Lapis Lazuli』というね、タイトルを付けさせていただきました。この『Lapis Lazuli』というのはですね、
and I've titled it "Lapis Lazuli." This "Lapis Lazuli," well,
いつも、あの、アルバムには「L」の文字がついてるんですけども、今回も「L」の文字から始まる
my albums always have the letter "L" in the title, and this time it's "Lapis Lazuli," starting with the letter "L."
『Lapis Lazuli』という言葉で、こちらですね、あの、意味がですね、えー、成功に導く、だったりとか、
The meaning of this word is "leading to success,"
あとは結構、あの、勝利へと、勝利を掴み取る、みたいな、えー、意味合いが込められておりまして、
and it also carries the meaning of "toward victory" or "grasping victory."
なんとこちらアルバムはですね、VS、戦いをテーマにした曲ばかりになっておりますので、
And this album, well, the theme is "VS" or "fight," and it's full of songs with that theme.
そういった意味合いも込めて、『Lapis Lazuli』という名前を付けさせていただきました。さらに！
So with that meaning in mind, I chose the name "Lapis Lazuli." Furthermore!
なんとですね、秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんでも、リリース記念ライブをやらせていただくことになりましたー！
I'll be holding a release commemorative live at the Akihabara Gamers main store!
いえーい！なんと、ミニライブも開催ということで。本日ですね、えー、12時半から予約開始となっているので、
Yay! I'll be doing a mini-live as well. Pre-orders started today at 12:30 PM,
もうすでに、えー、予約ができる状態になっております。皆様も見えますかね？えー、画面の左下、
so you can already pre-order it. Can everyone see? In the bottom left of the screen,
左下にボタンありますか？みんなある？ボタン。あるかしら。そこからですね、購入ボタンがありますので、
is there a button? Does everyone see the button? I wonder if it's there. There's a buy button there,
そこから予約ができるようになりましたので、ぜひぜひ、こちらから予約してみてください。
and you can pre-order through it, so please do try pre-ordering from there.
ということで、アルバムの詳細をね、えー、パッとお話しさせていただこうかなと思うんですけども、
So, I'd like to quickly talk about the details of the album.
おめでとうありがとう、みんな。収録楽曲についてはこちらになります。ドゥルン！
Thank you for the congratulations, everyone. Here are the included tracks. Ta-da!
はい、えー、先行リリースしております『ZIG-ZAG』を始め、先ほども言いましたVS、戦いをテーマにした、
Yes, starting with "ZIG-ZAG," which has been pre-released, as I mentioned earlier, it's themed around "VS" and "fighting,"
全10曲が収録されています。6曲目にはですね、皆さん、お分かりですか？
and includes a total of 10 tracks. For the 6th track, do you see it?
フィーチャリング・ラプラス・ダークネスということで、えー、ラプラスも続く...
It's featuring La+ Darknesss. La+ also...
1. BAN
2. DARE?
3. ZIG-ZAG
4. get lucky
5. Smart
6. アナスタシス・ガール
7. Sweet Temptation
8. 余計なお世話だ！！
9. アン・シンデレラ
10. 光り輝く明日への讃歌
1. BAN
2. DARE?
3. ZIG-ZAG
4. get lucky
5. Smart
6. Anastasis Girl
7. Sweet Temptation
8. None of Your Business!!
9. Un-Cinderella
10. Anthem for a Shining Tomorrow
えっと、一緒に歌った曲も収録はされております。
Also, the songs we sang together are included.
そしてですね、いろいろまあ言いたいことはあるんですけども、
And then, well, there's a lot I want to say,
一つ一つ言いたいんですけど、ちょっとお時間がないので、
I want to talk about each one, but we're short on time,
えー、10曲目の『抗う君へのレクイエム』という曲はですね、
so, the 10th track, 'Requiem for the Resisting You',
とあるアニメのイメージソングになっておりますので、
is an image song for a certain anime,
これからいろいろ情報が出てくると思いますので、
so more information will be coming out soon,
楽しみに待っていただければなと思います。
so please look forward to it.
そして、完全生産限定盤はこんな感じになっております。どうぞ！
And, the Complete Production Limited Edition looks like this. Here it is!
お、どうぞ！あ、こっちだ。どうぞ！あ、こっちだ。あはは。
Oh, here! Ah, this way. Here! Ah, over here. Hahaha.
えー、スライドボックス式でですね、あの、
It's a slide-box style, and, well,
二人の鷹嶺ルイを、あの、離したりくっつけたりできる。おしゃれでしょ？
you can separate or join the two Takane Luis. Stylish, right?
しかも、『Liberty』と同じSOLANIさんが、えー、イラストを担当してくださいました。
Moreover, SOLANI, who did 'Liberty', was in charge of the illustrations.
めちゃくちゃかっこよくなってないですか？
Doesn't it look incredibly cool?
ぜひぜひね、あの、戦わせたり離したりして遊んでみてください。
Please try playing with them, like making them fight or separating them.
他にも、このようなグッズもございます。
There are also other goods like these.
完全生産限定盤にはですね、えー、今までリリースした楽曲のジャケットを、
The Complete Production Limited Edition includes a jacket illustration book
えー、入れ込んだジャケットイラストブック。これね、私が欲しいって言ったんですよ。
featuring the jackets of all the songs released so far. I said I wanted this.
そしたらね、む、無理やり欲しいって言ったんですけど、なんと実現をしてくださいまして、
I insisted on wanting it, and they actually made it happen,
今までの、えー、リリースした楽曲のジャケットが一冊の本になって見れるやつになっております。
so it's a book where you can see all the jackets of the songs released so far.
いや、みんな欲しかったっしょ？いや、私が欲しいものはきっとみんなが欲しいと思いまして、
I mean, you all wanted it, right? I thought if I want it, you all probably do too,
こちらちょっと無理やりに作っていただきました。関係者の皆さんありがとうございました。
so I had them make it even though it was a stretch. Thank you to everyone involved.
そしてですね、オリジナル缶バッジも2種類ついて、そしてそして、
And then, there are two types of original pin badges, and, and,
今回もですね、完全生産限定盤にだけになるんですけれども、
this time too, only for the Complete Production Limited Edition,
直筆サイン入りジャケットカードを、購入者全員、皆さんに、直筆サインさせていただきますので、
I will personally sign jacket cards for every single purchaser,
ぜひぜひ完全生産限定盤、いろんな特典がありますので、買っていただけますと幸いでございます。
so I'd be happy if you'd buy the Limited Edition with its various bonuses.
さらに、通常盤はこちら。
And furthermore, here's the Regular Edition.
はい、通常盤にはですね、ランダムアナザージャケット1枚入り、
Yes, the Regular Edition contains one random alternative jacket,
全5種類ある中の1枚が入っております。
one out of five different types is included.
そしてこちらもですね、数量限定、ランダムで、鷹嶺ルイの直筆サイン、そして、
And these also, in limited quantities and randomly, will have my signature and...
コメントも付いてきます。直筆コメントも付いてきます。
...a comment. A handwritten comment will also be included.
ちょっとこちらはランダムになっちゃうんですけれども、ぜひぜひ、皆さんに当たりますように。
It's random, but I hope many of you get one.
通常盤もぜひ買ってみてください。そしてそして、
Please try buying the Regular Edition too. And, and...
各ショップの、えー、法人特典はこちらになります。ドドン。
...the store-specific corporate bonuses for each shop are here. Ta-da!
Amazon様、マウスパッドだったり、色々なね、お店で、色々な特典がついておりますので、
There are various bonuses at different shops, like a mousepad from Amazon,
皆さん欲しいものがあればそちらで予約してくださると嬉しいでございます。
so if there's something you want, I'd be happy if you'd pre-order there.
また詳細などは、ポストしますので、そちらで詳しく見ていってください。
I'll post the details later, so please check there for more information.
はい、さらに、こちら。
Yes, and furthermore, this.
先ほどもお伝えしました、秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店様にて、12月7日に、
As I mentioned earlier, at the Gamers Akihabara main store on December 7th,
リリース記念ミニライブの開催が決定しました！
a release commemorative mini-live has been confirmed!
ゲーマーズさんでアルバムを購入した人の中から抽選で、ミニライブにご招待をさせていただきます。
We'll invite people to the mini-live by lottery from those who bought the album at Gamers.
ぜひゲーマーズさんでもアルバムを買ってくださると嬉しいでございます。
So I'd be happy if you'd buy the album at Gamers too.
ということで、えー、今回ですね、あの、皆さんの左下にあるボタンではですね、
So, this time, the button at the bottom left for you all,
完全生産版と通常盤のところにECサイトに飛ぶのかな？
will it take you to the EC site for the Limited and Regular editions?
多分オフィシャルサイトに飛びますので、えー、皆さんそちらで、
It'll probably take you to the official site, so everyone,
完全生産限定盤だったりとかが欲しいよっていう方はそちらで予約をしていただきまして、
those who want the Complete Production Limited Edition can pre-order there,
ちょっと他のショップさんで予約をしたいよという方はね、詳細後ほど、
and for those who want to pre-order at other shops, details will be provided later...
えー、X、そして概要欄にも貼らせていただきますので、そちらでチェックをしていただけると嬉しいでございます。
...on X, and I'll also post them in the description, so I'd be happy if you'd check them there.
いや、ラピスラズリ。しかもですね、ちょっとラピスラズリって、あの、誕生月、誕生石？が9月と12月ということで、
Lapis Lazuli. And, well, since the birthstones for Lapis Lazuli are for September and December,
なんと9月に私重大発表をして、えー、12月に発売っていうね。
I made a big announcement in September, and then the release is in December.
あ、これたまたまなんですけど、あ、たまたまって言わないほうがいいよね。
Oh, this was a coincidence, but I probably shouldn't say it was a coincidence.
あ、これね、あの、仕掛けなんですね。これ、仕掛けさせていただきました。
Ah, this is, well, it was planned. I planned it that way.
偶然じゃなくて、ちゃんと、ちゃんと、ちゃんと考えました。あはは。
It's not a coincidence, I thought about it very, very carefully. Hahaha.
なので、私の夢であり...
So, it's my dream...
全国流通版のセカンドアルバム、ぜひぜひ皆様、ご購入いただけますと幸いです。
I would be very grateful if you would all purchase the nationwide distribution version of my second album.
よろしくお願いいたします。
Thank you very much.
それでは、まだまだ歌っていきたいと思います。
Well then, I'd like to keep on singing.
このあともまだまだ告知がございますので、お楽しみに。
There are still more announcements to come, so please look forward to them.
ちょっと水を飲んでもいいですか？
Can I drink some water?
水飲んでもいいですね。水飲みます。
It's okay to drink water, right? I'll drink some water.
ちょっと待ってください。
Please wait a moment.
飲みました。
I've finished.
ということで、まだお一人、ゲストが出てない方がいらっしゃいますね。
So, there is still one more guest who hasn't appeared yet.
その方はいつ出るんでしょうか？
I wonder when they will appear?
お見逃しなくということで、続いての曲行きましょうか。
Don't miss out. Let's move on to the next song.
皆様準備は大丈夫ですか？
Are you all ready?
準備は大丈夫ですね。
You're ready, right?
それでは。
Well then.
はい、それでは聴いてください。ジグザグ。
Yes, please listen. ZIG-ZAG.
One, two, three, four!
ということで、もう一人の特別ゲストを呼びたいと思います！
With that, I'd like to call out another special guest!
星街すいせい！盛り上げていきましょう！
Hoshimachi Suisei! Let's get hyped!
「幸せ？」ってささやいた　吐息がらったったったった
The breath that whispered "Are you happy?" went ra-ta-ta-ta-ta
こびりついて離れば　ダメだらったったったった
If it sticks and won't come off, it's no good, ra-ta-ta-ta-ta
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't remember my tasteless and odorless life
忘れたいから歌った　馬鹿だらったったったった
I sang because I wanted to forget, what a fool, ra-ta-ta-ta-ta
恨むことも憎むことも
Neither resenting nor hating
賢くないゆえできなかった
Because I wasn't smart, I couldn't do it
これが君の結末ならば
If this is your end
笑ってしまいたいほど
So much that I want to laugh
嘘 嘘 嘘 (嘘つき)
Lies, lies, lies (Liar)
痛い痛い痛い痛いな　奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
It hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping for a bit of a miracle
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌　たちが悪いわ
No more, no, no, no, no, it's nasty
辛い辛い辛い辛いな　可笑しなとこ全部抉り取って
It's painful, painful, painful, painful, gouging out all the strange parts
薄情で結構　好きに呼んでよ
I'm fine with being heartless, call me whatever you like
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです　ですですですです
I want to say bye-bye to trauma, it's true, true, true, true
私、甘え上手になれなかった
I couldn't become good at being spoiled
可愛げとかが足りなかった
I didn't have enough cuteness
後悔がうるさい夜だ
It's a night where regrets are loud
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば　きっといいことあるさと
If I just accept that the past is the past, surely something good will happen
かそれくらい　百も承知だらったったった
Or something like that, I'm well aware, ra-ta-ta-ta-ta
願うことも祈ることも
Neither wishing nor praying
許されないから黒く染めた
Because it's not allowed, I dyed it black
元の色も思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color
絡まった運命の　糸 糸 糸
The tangled threads of fate, threads, threads, threads
痛い痛い痛い痛いな　悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
It hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, acting like a tragic heroine
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌　諦めちまえば
No more, no, no, no, no, if I just give up
会いたい会いたい会いたいな　思考回路混んがらがっちゃって
I want to meet, meet, meet, my thoughts are getting all tangled up
明日またきっと壊すけどいいの
I'll surely break it again tomorrow, but that's okay
トラウマよ咲いて散るのです　ですですですです
Trauma, bloom and scatter, it's true, true, true, true
夢の中で君と　手を繋いでいるの
I'm holding hands with you in a dream
何も知らない　あの頃の二人のままで
Just like the two of us back then, when we knew nothing
でも分かっているよ　すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know that I'll wake up soon
それならばいっそ
In that case, I'd rather
君の手でそっと
By your hand, softly
トドメ刺してほら
Deliver the finishing blow, look
今今今
Now, now, now
痛い痛い痛い痛いな　奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
It hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping for a bit of a miracle
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌　たちが悪いわ
No more, no, no, no, no, it's nasty
辛い辛い辛い辛いな　可笑しなとこ全部抉り取って
It's painful, painful, painful, painful, gouging out all the strange parts
薄情で結構　好きに呼んでよ
I'm fine with being heartless, call me whatever you like
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです　ですですですです
I want to say bye-bye to trauma, it's true, true, true, true
すいちゃん来てくれてありがとうー！
Sui-chan, thank you for coming!
イェーイ！しゅるたんと歌えて楽しかったぜ！
Yay! It was fun singing with Shul-tan!
いや嬉しいぜ！
I'm so happy!
ジグザグ、ジグザグ、ジグザグ！
ZIG-ZAG, ZIG-ZAG, ZIG-ZAG!
うわー！ということで皆さん、すいちゃんが来てくれました！
Wow! So everyone, Sui-chan is here!
来ましたよ！
I'm here!
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいでーす！
The diamond in the rough that appeared like a comet! I'm virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃーん！今日も可愛い！
Sui-chan! You're cute today too!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ルイ、セカンドアルバム発売決定おめでとう！
Lui, congratulations on the decision to release your second album!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そう、いっぱい、あの、いっぱい、いっぱい相談しました。
Yes, I... well, I consulted with her a lot.
いっぱい、いっぱい確かにルイから聞いたかも、
A lot, a lot. I certainly heard from you about it.
なんか曲、結構知ってるかも。
I feel like I know the song pretty well now.
そう、いっぱい、いっぱい相談しました、すいちゃんに。
Yes, I consulted with Suisei-chan a lot.
このジグザグもね、実はちょっとリリース前から聞いてて。
I actually heard 'ZIGZAG' even before its release.
はい。はい。今日、そう、今日はですね、
Right. Yes. Today... well, today,
ジグザグをすいちゃんと歌いたかった理由はですね、
the reason I wanted to sing 'ZIGZAG' with Suisei-chan is,
いっぱい、いっぱい相談をしたっていうのと、
well, really, I consulted with her a lot,
あと曲がね、タイトルを一緒に考えてくれたんですよね、ジグザグという。
and she also thought of the title with me. The title 'ZIGZAG'.
そうなんですよ。一番最初タイトル本当は違ったんだよね。
That's right. The title was actually different at first, wasn't it?
そう、そうなんですよ。そこからどうかな、って言って、
Yes, that's right. From there, we were like 'How about this?'
え、ジグザグってトラウマって意味あるらしいよ、みたいになって。
and then, 'Hey, I heard "zigzag" can mean trauma!'
なって、一緒にね、え、ジグザグ良くない？みたいな。
And then, together, we were like, 'Isn't "ZIGZAG" good?'
良くない？みたいな。間にハイフンとか入れようぜ、って
'Isn't it good?' 'Let's put a hyphen in the middle.'
おしゃれじゃない？みたいな。
'Isn't that stylish?'
って言ったんですよね。たくさん、たくさん相談をしまして。
That's what we said. We consulted many, many times.
はい。で、ジグザグすいちゃんに合いそうだな、みたいな。
And I thought 'ZIGZAG' would suit Suisei-chan.
え、でもこれね、歌っててね、楽しいの。
But you know, singing this is fun.
楽しい、楽しい。楽しいでしょ？
It's fun. It's fun, isn't it?
楽しいんですよ。
It is fun.
いや、これ楽しいですよすごい。楽しいんですよ。ぜひ。
No, this is really fun. It's fun. Please listen to it.
しかもルイとね、やっぱその声質というか、
And with Lui, that voice quality...
このなんだろう、低音歌う組というか、として、
how should I say, as the 'low voice singing group,'
なんか合ってるなっていうのもすごい思ったし、なんか歌ってて楽しかったです。
I really felt we matched well, so it was fun to sing.
いや、もう嬉しい。もうジグザグ歌うんだったら、
I'm so happy. I said if I was going to sing 'ZIGZAG',
すいちゃんと歌いたい、って言って、もう絶対すいちゃんと歌う、って言って。
I wanted to sing it with Suisei-chan. I said I'd definitely sing it with her.
キャー。すげー。
Kyah! Awesome!
で、あの、呼びしたら快諾をしてくださいました。本当にありがとうございます。
And when I invited her, she readily agreed. Thank you so much.
忙しい中でありがとうございます。
Thank you for doing this in your busy schedule.
いえいえ。いえ。そんなもうね、もう生出演なんかもういつでも呼んでください、そんな。
No, no. Not at all. You can call me for a live appearance anytime.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
コメントの皆さんもね、はい。どうも、どうも。
Everyone in the comments too... yes. Hello, hello.
あ、いい、かっこいい、かっこいい、合ってる合ってる、わかるわかるって、ほらね、言ってるよね。
Oh, 'It's cool, it's cool,' 'They match,' 'I get it.' See, they're saying it.
いや、本当に一緒に歌えて、まあ本当に緊張したんだけど、一緒に歌えて良かった。
Really, being able to sing together... well, I was really nervous, but I'm glad we could.
しかも2回目なんです、一緒に二人で歌ったの。
And it's the second time the two of us have sung together.
そうなんですよね。
That's right.
そうなんです。前はMGDのファーストでね、
Yes. Before it was at MGD's 1st live.
バグ。
'Bug'.
そう、バグで。今度はジグザグ。
Right, with 'Bug'. This time it's 'ZIGZAG'.
ジグザグ。
'ZIGZAG'.
次は何になるんでしょうか。
I wonder what will be next.
次は何グですか？
What kind of '-gu' will it be next?
何グになるんでしょうか。はい。どんどん今後も楽しみにしていただけたらなと思うんですけれども。
I wonder what it'll be. I hope you look forward to it in the future, but...
なんとまだ告知があるんです。
Actually, there's still another announcement.
えっ、そんなまさか。はい。
Eh, no way! Really?
なので、
So,
えっ、えっ、どんなやつ？
Eh, eh, what kind of announcement?
えっ、ちょっとこの、このアルバムに絡めたやつですよ。
Well, it's something related to this album.
えっ、何、何？気になる、気になる。
Eh, what is it? I'm curious, I'm curious.
気になる？じゃあ、一緒に見ようか。
Are you curious? Then, shall we watch it together?
え、見るんだ。一緒に見よう。
Eh, we're watching it? Let's watch it together.
はい。ということで、こちらをご覧ください。どうぞ。
Okay, everyone, please take a look at this. Here you go.
特報
Special News
知ってんぜ　知ってんぜ　存じ上げないわ
I know, I know, I don't know you at all
Who are you you you you? どっちお互い様
Who are you you you you? We're both in the same boat
Face to face こんにちは
Face to face, hello
夕闇も　飲んでたって　Upside down自分自分
Even if I'm drinking in the dusk, upside down, me, me
Look alike らいらくらい　らからからい　冗に載せて
Look alike, carefree, carefree, put it in a joke
手構えて構えて構え　おどけきな自分は
Get ready, get ready, get ready, the clownish me
自分の手で片付けましょう
I'll clean it up with my own hands
でかふーわーゆー　誰？
So who are you? Dare?
このあとOriginal Anime MV公開!
Original Anime MV release after this!
なんとセカンドアルバムより「誰？」
Actually, from the second album, 'Dare?'
本日24時に先行デジタルリリースがされます！
will have an advance digital release today at 24:00!
「誰？」　誰？誰？誰？えっ、これ誰？
'Dare?' Who? Who? Who? Eh, who is this?
えっ、こっちのルイはわかるけど、こっちのルイは誰？
I recognize this Lui, but who is this Lui?
誰なんだろう。
I wonder who it is.
誰なんだろう。えー、気になるよね。
I wonder who it is. Man, I'm curious.
気になるよね。実はこの曲作った人も気にならない？
Curious, right? Actually, aren't you curious who made this song too?
え、気になる。
Yes, I'm curious.
なんとマガンウィンクを作ってくれた、てにおはさんが今回も作成してくれたよ！
Believe it or not, Tenioha-san, who made 'Magan Wink', created this one too!
おー、てにおは節確かに感じる！感じる、感じる、めっちゃ感じる。
Oh, I can definitely feel the Tenioha style! I feel it, I feel it, I feel it a lot.
そして、この配信終了後にはMVが公開されます！
And after this stream ends, the MV will be released!
わー、MVさっき流れてたやつですね！
Wow, the MV that was playing just now!
そうなんですよ。なんと、あの、鷹嶺ルイ史上、もう今回、鷹嶺ルイ史上いっぱいあるんだけど、
That's right. And, for the first time in Takane Lui's history... well, there are many firsts this time,
鷹嶺ルイ史上初のオリジナルアニメMV、フルアニメMVをね、作らせていただきました！
but this is Takane Lui's first original anime MV, a full anime MV!
わー！すごかった、めっちゃヌルヌル動いてた。
Wow! That was amazing, it moved so smoothly.
ヌルヌル動いてたでしょ。しかも、なんか私が好きそうな絵のタッチじゃない？
It moved smoothly, didn't it? Plus, doesn't it have an art style that I'd like?
おー、確かにね。
Oh, that's true.
なんと私ですね、すごいもうかねてよりあのMV作っていただきたいなと、
Actually, I... had been wanting to have an MV made by
あの思っていた安田現象さんに！
Yasuda Gensho-san for a long time!
あの！あの安田現象さんに！あの、安田現象さんですか？
That one! That Yasuda Gensho-san! Wait, you mean THE Yasuda Gensho-san?
そうです。大丈夫ですか？
Yes. Is everything okay?
安田現象さんですか？
Yasuda Gensho-san?
はい。あの...
Yes. Well...
安田現象さんに作成をしていただいたフルアニメーションMVとなっております。
It's a full-animation MV created by Gensho Yasuda.
わあ、すごい。サムネもかわいい。
Wow, amazing. The thumbnail is cute too.
かわいいでしょ？
It's cute, right?
あっかんべーしてます。
It's sticking its tongue out.
あっかんべーしてるね。
It is sticking its tongue out, isn't it?
ということでこのね、誰というのは...
So, this "DARE" refers to...
内面にいる、まあ私...
An "another self" inside me...
私結構内面にアンチ持ってるんですけど。
I actually have quite an "anti" inside me.
お、そうなの。
Oh, really?
鷹嶺ルイのアンチを持ってるんですけど。
I have an "anti" of Takane Lui inside.
「お前本当にこれできんのか？」みたいなね。
"Like, 'Can you really do this?'"
「お前本当にやれんのか？」みたいな。
"Like, 'Are you really up for it?'"
え、このなんか感情って誰なん？みたいな。
Yeah, like, "Who is this feeling?"
おお。
Oh.
え、私なん？私なの？なんで私、私を否定してるの？みたいな。
Is it me? Me? Why am I denying myself?
そういうね、誰っていう...
That kind of "DARE"...
深い...
Deep...
そういう楽曲に仕上がっておりますし、
It's that kind of song,
それを Who are you DARE. 誰！
And that... Who are you DARE. DARE!
誰！
DARE!
誰なの？私なの？
Is it DARE? Is it me?
誰なの！？
Who is it!?
という、え、曲になっておりますので、
That's the kind of song it is,
これからちょっとMVもね、プレミア公開させていただきますので。
I'll be premiering the MV soon.
ぜひぜひ、楽しんでいただければなと思いますし、
I hope you'll enjoy it,
結構耳に残るサウンドになってますのでね。
It's got a very catchy sound.
ね、もう今、後ろでうっすら流れてますけど。
Right, it's already playing faintly in the background.
え、これは早くフル聴きたいし、
Oh, I want to hear the full version soon,
もうなんなら今から歌ってもらえませんか？
And if possible, could you sing it now?
え、え、なに？え？
Wait, what?
え、一緒に歌いますか？
Wait, will you sing with me?
え、あ、うーんと、じゃじゃじゃ、ヘイ、ヘイ...
Oh, uh... well, well, hey, hey...
ちょ、歌いなそうですね。
Wait, it doesn't sound like you're going to sing.
ということで、この後、実は誰を先行で歌わせていただきます！
So, after this, I'll actually be performing "DARE" early!
うわー！そうなの！？
Wow! Really!?
じゃあ私は端から見てますということで。
Then I'll watch from the side.
えー、待っててね。ご飯食べ、ご飯食べよう、一緒に。
Wait for me. Let's eat together.
あー、わかった。じゃあ舞台袖で見てますわ。
Oh, okay. I'll watch from the wings then.
この後、じゃあご飯ということで。よろしくお願いします。
Then food after this. Looking forward to it.
てか Who are you 誰。じゃ。
Anyway, who are you, DARE. See ya.
ありがとう。
Thanks.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
すいちゃんでした！ありがとう、みんな！ありがとー。
That was Sui-chan! Thanks everyone! Thank you.
ありがとー。
Thank you.
ということで、心強かった助っ人、すいちゃんもいなくなり、
So, with my reliable helper Sui-chan gone,
私一人でですね、新曲「Lapis Lazuli」にも入っております曲、
Alone, I will perform a song included in my new single "Lapis Lazuli",
「DARE」を歌わせていただきます。
The song "DARE".
ちょっと水飲んでいいですか？水飲みますよ。水飲みます。
Can I have some water? I'm going to drink some water. Drinking water.
はい、ということで戻ってまいりました。
Alright, I'm back.
それでは皆さん、聴いてください。
Now everyone, please listen.
「DARE」。
"DARE".
誰だ　誰　そちら様　どちら様
Who are you? Who? Who are you? Which one are you?
果てさて　Who are you? How are you? お元気で　一足お先に
Well, well. Who are you? How are you? Take care, I'm going ahead.
てか Who are you?
Anyway, who are you?
DARE!? / 作詞・作曲・編曲：てにをは
DARE!? / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: teniwoha
昨日の自分が描いた縁かな　はみ出さないように
Is it the edge my yesterday's self drew? So it doesn't stick out.
一回り小さな円を描くような
Drawing a circle one size smaller.
ボールのバウンドが少しずつ低くなる様を
The way a ball's bounce gradually gets lower.
術もなく眺めているような気分でしょう？
It feels like you're just watching it helplessly, doesn't it?
ところで貴方
By the way, you.
誰　誰　誰　誰！　誰　誰　誰　誰！
Who, who, who, who! Who, who, who, who!
おや　果てさて　存じ上げないわ　誰？
Oh, well, well. I don't know you. Who?
Who are you you you you? どちら様？ Face to face　こんにちは
Who are you, you, you, you? Which one are you? Face to face, hello.
You and me　混ざって　だって　Upside down　自分　自分
You and me mixed up, because, upside down, self, self.
Look-alike　だらけだ　ガラガラ　通せんせ　捕まえ　捕まえ　捕まえわ誰？
Full of look-alikes, clattering, let me pass, catch, catch, who are you catching?
昨日の自分は自分の手で片付けましょう
Let's clean up yesterday's self with our own hands.
てか Who are you? 誰？
Anyway, who are you? Who?
鏡の端から確か私を見張り続けてる
From the edge of the mirror, I'm sure you're keeping a watch on me.
なのでぐっと背筋伸ばし微笑むの
So I straighten my back and smile.
花は誰に見られずとも美しく咲くと言うけど
They say flowers bloom beautifully even if no one sees them,
盾や矛にもそっぽ向かれたら咲き方を改めるだろう
But if even shields and spears turn away, they'd probably change how they bloom.
DARE DARE DARE...
誰　誰　誰　存じ上げないわ　誰？
Who, who, who. I don't know you. Who?
Who are you you you you? どちら様？ Face to face　こんばんは
Who are you, you, you, you? Which one are you? Face to face, good evening.
You and me　混ざって　だって　Upside down　自分　自分
You and me mixed up, because, upside down, self, self.
Look-alike　だらけだ　ガラガラ　通せんせ　捕まえ...
Full of look-alikes, clattering, let me pass, catch...
My favorite word は誰？
Who is my favorite word?
愛したのは私よ　私を倒させて
It was me who loved you, let me be defeated
How are you? How are you? How about you? DARE!!
Look like a...
Look like a, a, a...
Me!
Look like a...
誰だ　誰だ　そちら様
Who is it? Who is it? You there?
どちら様
Who are you?
反転させて
Invert it
これは誰だ
Who is this?
誰であれ
Whoever it is
見せつけるだけ
I'll just show off
Take a look my dare
Have a nice dare
はい！ということで今日のライブはこれにて終了となります
All right! With that, today's live stream comes to an end.
皆さん本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much!
改めて告知をさせていただきます
I have some announcements to make once again.
セカンドアルバム「Lapis Lazuli」が12月3日に発売されます！
My 2nd album "Lapis Lazuli" will be released on December 3rd!
予約はもうできますので、こちらかな？こちらからぜひぜひ予約をしてください
Pre-orders are now open, so please pre-order from here or maybe here!
もうすごく頑張った楽曲、頑張って頑張って歌った楽曲ばかりになりますので
It's full of songs that I worked really hard on and sang with all my heart,
ぜひぜひ早く皆さんに聴いていただきたいなと思いますので
so I really want you all to hear them as soon as possible.
ぜひセカンドアルバムもよろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to the 2nd album!
そして豪華なスライドボックスパッケージでイラストブックや缶バッジ、
There's the Limited First Edition in a deluxe slide box package with an art book, badges,
直筆サイン入りのジャケットカードなどが付いてくる完全生産限定盤
and a jacket card with a hand-written signature.
そしてランダムアナザージャケット全5種から1枚、数量限定ランダムで
And the Standard Edition comes with one of five random alternative jackets,
直筆サインとメッセージが付く通常盤
with a limited number featuring a hand-written signature and message.
各種法人特典も盛りだくさんでございます！
There are also plenty of store-specific bonuses!
秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんにてリリース記念のミニライブもやる予定でございます！
I'm also planning to hold a release commemoration mini-live at Akihabara Gamers Main Store!
そして先ほど歌いました「DARE!!」本日24時にデジタルリリースされますし
Also, the song I just sang, "DARE!!", will be released digitally at midnight today,
この後すぐフルアニメーションMVも公開されます！
and a full animation MV will be released right after this!
このまま見ていただければ、確か自動でMVに飛びますので
If you keep watching, I believe it will automatically jump to the MV,
ぜひぜひフルアニメーション、私自身初のフルアニメーションになっておりますので
so please check it out. It's my very first full animation MV.
可愛く仕上がったので見ていただけると嬉しいでございます！
It turned out really cute, so I'd be happy if you'd watch it!
はい、今回重大告知ライブということで、皆さんソロライブなんじゃないかってすごい予想をしてくださっていたんですけれども
Now, since this was a major announcement live stream, many of you were guessing it might be a solo live,
私の方はまだソロライブは決まっておりません
but a solo live hasn't been decided yet.
ですがですね、私音楽をやりたいと心に決めてから、夢であるファーストアルバムがリリースできたり
However, since I decided to pursue music, I've been able to release my dream first album,
そしてファーストアルバムを皆さんが買ってくださったから、こうしてセカンドアルバムを全国流通として発売することができました
and because you all bought it, I'm now able to release my 2nd album for nationwide distribution.
1000万再生のMVが2つもできましたし、そのほかの楽曲もたくさんたくさんみんなに愛してもらって
I've had two MVs reach 10 million views, and my other songs have been loved by so many people.
再生数もすごい伸びて、もうみんなのおかげでですね、私こんなに音楽をやっていてよかったなと
The view counts have grown so much, and thanks to everyone, I'm so glad I've been doing music.
今でも, そしてこれからもきっと, 思うと思います
I feel that way now, and I'm sure I'll continue to feel that way.
ソロライブ、次はですね、夢を一つずつ叶えてきたからこそ、次はもうソロライブしかないやろ！
A solo live... next, because I've been making my dreams come true one by one, there's nothing left but a solo live!
なので、必ず皆さんと一緒にソロライブを夢見て、またここから走り出したいなと思います
So, I want to dream of a solo live together with you all and start running again from here.
ぜひぜひ皆さん、ファーストに引き続きセカンドアルバムもお手元に取っていただけると嬉しいです
Everyone, I'd be happy if you'd pick up the 2nd album just as you did the first.
なので、これからまた鷹嶺ルイと一緒にソロライブを目指しましょう！目指してくれますか？
So, let's aim for a solo live together with Takane Lui! Will you aim for it with me?
ん？ん？目指してくれるか？
Hm? Hm? Will you?
もちろん、ええ、ありがとう！
Of course! Yeah, thank you!
はい、もう本当にみんなの力がないと、私はきっとソロライブに到達できないと思うので
Yes, without everyone's support, I'm sure I wouldn't be able to reach a solo live,
私も頑張りますが、みんなも一緒に走り続けていただけると嬉しいです
so while I'll do my best, I'd be happy if you'd keep running alongside me.
ルイ友のみんな、そしてルイのことはまあ2番手3番手ぐらいに推してるよというみんな、
To all my Ruitomo, those who support me as their second or third favorite,
そしてホロリスの皆さん、そしてこれからまた出会うであろう鷹嶺ルイを知っていただける皆さん
all the Hololive fans, and everyone who will get to know Takane Lui in the future...
是非これからも鷹嶺ルイをよろしくお願いします。
Please continue to support Takane Lui from now on.
はい。ということで、
Yes. So...
じゃあ次のね。ま、次、重大告知がある時にはもう、
the next... well, when there's another major announcement,
超重大告知としてね。
I'll work hard so I can announce
そのライブが発表できるように、これからも頑張ります。
that live show as a "super major announcement" next time!
みんな、本当に今日はありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for today!
セカンドアルバム楽しみに待っててね。
Please look forward to the 2nd album.
これからどんどん情報が出てくると思いますので。
More information will be coming out soon, so...
お楽しみに！
look forward to it!
またね！
See you!
重大告知
Major Announcement
Lapis Lazuli